Yared Gari

■ yaredbacha@gmail.com
■ 2066410154
■ Seattle, WA in Linkedin
■ GitHub
■ Portfolio

Summary

Proactive and multidisciplinary Software Engineer with experience in web development and data analytics. With 2+ years of experience as a Frontend developer and 8 years as a university lecturer and researcher. Passionate about learning technologies and staying up-to-date with industry trends to deliver value added products. Seeking a Software developer position to contribute to company's goals and push the boundaries of technology.

Professional Experience

Software Engineer, *Mckinsey & Company* 03/2022 - present | Atlanata, US

- Collaborated on the development of the McKinsey Quarterly Digital edition and McKinsey Insight store, which added thousands of new users to our user base in the first month.
- Implemented unit and integration test suites that resulted in a drastic decrease in production issues.
- Identified, debugged, tested, and resolved various issues within our codebase to improve the overall quality of our application.
- Conducted A/B experiments using Adobe Analytics with my team to optimize Mckinsey.com, identifying opportunities that increased our user acquisition rate by more than 20%..

Junior software Engineer(Intern), *Axious Solutions* 12/2020 - 03/2022 | Washington DC, US

- Collaborated with senior engineers on bug fixing, feature development and testing.
- Attended training and development sessions.

Lecturer and Visiting Researcher, *Bahir Dar* University, University of Calgary & Wisconsin-madison 06/2012 - 12/2020

Bahir Dar, Calgary, Madison | ETH, US

- Taught hydraulic structure I and II courses
- Published two research articles on international
- Supervised 3 batches of undergraduate students.

Skills

JavaScript, React, React Native, Redux, Next js, Typescript, jQuery, Tailwind, React Testing library, jest, unit and integration testing, Accessibility, Responsive design, Git, GitHub, Bootstrap, Webpack, Figma, HTML5/XML/JSON, CSS3/SCSS, AB test/adobe analytics, code debugging, agile/Scrum Frontend Skills

Node, Express, Sequelize ORM, REST API, GraphQL, Docker, AWS, CI/CD, SQL, MYSQL, Mongo DB Backend Skills

communication, team work, growth mindset, problem solving, attension to details, time management, persistance and protectiveness Soft skills

Certificates

- AWS cloud practitioner
- Certified Javascript developer
- React framework Nano degree

Education

Full Stack developer,

Multiverse Bootcamp (15 months) 2022 | NY, US

Java Full Stack developer,

Atlanta Technical College/Generation USA (6 months) 2021 | Atlanta, US

Masters In Hydraulic Engineering,

Bahir Dar Institute of Technology 2011 - 2012 | Bahir Dar, Ethiopia

Bachelor in Water Resource Engineering,

Bahir Dar University 2005 – 2009 | Bahir Dar, Ethiopia

Publications

link ♂